Guide to the Yale University Women's Organization Oral History Project Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale University Women's Organization oral history project records
1965-2002
RU 924
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
The materials consist of audiotapes, a videotape, transcripts, and project and background files relating to "One Story, Many Voices: An Oral History of the Yale University Women's Organization."
Yale University Women's Organization
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 40 (YRG 40), Records of Yale clubs, societies and organizations.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Yale University Women's Organization, 2003.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by record type.
Biographical / Historical
The Yale University Women's Organization was established in 1965. The organization is open to women members of the Yale community, including faculty, staff, wives of faculty and staff, and other women affiliated with the university. Its main activities include educational lectures, social events, and a scholarship program. The organization undertook an oral history project in 1999, culminating in videotape, One Story, Many Voices: An Oral History of the Yale University Women's Organization. The project documents the founding and activities of the organization, spousal privileges, the Yale Newcomer's Club, and the Information and Counseling Center for Women (Yale Women's Center).
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of audiotapes, a videotape, transcripts, and project and background files relating to "One Story, Many Voices: An Oral History of the Yale University Women's Organization."
College teachers' spouses -- Social networks; College teachers -- Societies, etc.; Universities and colleges -- Employees -- Societies, etc.; Women -- Education (Higher); Women -- Societies and clubs; Audiotapes; Oral histories (document genres); Videotapes; Yale Newcomer's Club; Yale University Women's Organization; Yale University -- Employees -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Faculty -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- History -- 20th Century; Yale University -- Societies, etc.
- Yale University Women's Organization history project records, 2000-2002; Accession 2003-A-076
  Scope and Contents
  The records are arranged in two sections: Project and Background Files and Interviews. The project and background files include a subject index and an appendix of material related to the history of the Yale University Women's Organization, which supplements the information provided by the interviewees. Cross references link specific interviews to related material in the appendix.
  - Project and background files
    - Subject index with numbered list of interviewees and interviewers (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Appendix, related materials, 1965-2002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Procedures, forms, video script, 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Interview agreements, 2000-2002 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Comment sheets, interviewers (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Comment sheets, reviewers, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Interviews
    - Transcripts
      - Ahlstrom-Ruthman, Nancy, 2000 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Altman, Ann, 2000 November 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Bollier, Trudy, 2002 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Childs, Ann, 2000 October 26 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Culler, Helen, 2000 December 6 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Drabkin, Meryl, 2000 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Howe, Lynn, 2000 November 4 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Marsden, Connie, 2000 October 19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Peterson, Doris, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Pfisterer, Hortense, 2001 January 8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Pincus (Russell), Cynthia, 2000 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Pollard, Pat Gordon, 2001 January 23 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Radding, Natalie, 2000 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Ross, Kay (20), 2001 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Sandweiss, Letha, 2001 December 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Schiff, Judith, 2001 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Schoolfield, Gloria, 2001 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Schütz, Barbara, 2001 February 27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Sherman, Martha, 2000 November 6 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Sirot, Carol, 2000 October 20 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Soell, Veronica, 2000 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Whitestone, Patricia, 2001 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Winkelman, Marion, 2000 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Audiotapes
      - Ahlstrom-Ruthman, Nancy, 2000 October 27; audiocassette (Box 2)
      - Altman, Ann, 2000 November 16; audiocassette (Box 3)
      - Bollier, Trudy, 2002 April 10; audiocassette (Box 5)
      - Childs, Ann, 2000 October 26; audiocassette (Box 6)
      - Culler, Helen, 2000 December 6; audiocassette (Box 7)
      - Drabkin, Meryl, 2000 April 25; audiocassette (Box 8)
      - Gall, Dolores, 2000 November 3; audiocassette (Box 9)
      - Gould, Carolyn, 2000 December 13; audiocassette (Box 10)
      - Hammond, Janet, 2001 February 10; audiocassette (Box 11)
      - Howe, Lynn, 2000 November 4; audiocassette (Box 12)
      - Marsden, Connie, 2000 October 19; audiocassette (Box 13)
      - Peterson, Doris, undated; audiocassette (Box 14)
      - Peterson, Mabel, 2000 January 15; audiocassette (Box 15)
      - Petrelli, Marion, 2001 January 29; audiocassette (Box 16)
      - Pfisterer, Hortense, 2001 January 8; audiocassette (Box 17)
      - Pincus (Russell), Cynthia, 2000 November 8; audiocassette (Box 18)
      - Pollard, Pat Gordon, 2001 January 23; audiocassette (Box 19)
      - Radding, Natalie, 2000 October 18; audiocassette (Box 20)
      - Rosenbaum, Nancy, 2001 January 29; audiocassette (Box 21)
      - Ross, Kay, 2001 January 16; audiocassette (Box 22)
      - Sandweiss, Letha, 2001 December 16; audiocassette (Box 23)
      - Schiff, Judith, 2001 October 27; audiocassette (Box 24)
      - Schoolfield, Gloria, 2001 February 20; audiocassette (Box 25)
      - Schütz, Barbara, 2001 February 27; audiocassette (Box 26)
        - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 26U1)
        - Use copy, compact disc (CD-R) (Box 26U2)
      - Sherman, Martha, 2000 November 6; audiocassette (Box 27)
      - Sirot, Carol, 2000 October 20; audiocassette (Box 28)
      - Soell, Veronica, 2000 November 2; audiocassette (Box 29)
      - Solnit, Martha, 2001 February 2; audiocassette (Box 30)
      - Thornton, Roberta, 2001 January 30; audiocassette (Box 31)
      - Trinkhaus, Sue, 2000 October 20; audiocassette (Box 32)
      - Turner, Jane, 2000 November 29; audiocassette (Box 33)
      - Westerfield, Carolyn, 2000 November 15; audiocassette (Box 34)
      - Whitestone, Patricia, 2001 November 17; audiocassette (Box 35)
      - Winkelman, Marion, 2000 November 28; audiocassette (Box 36)
      - Woods, Frances, 2000 October 27; audiocassette (Box 37)
    - One Story, Many Voices: An Oral History of the Yale University Women's Organization, videotape (VHS), 2001; videotape (VHS) (Box 4)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 4U)